Charles R. Martin Photographs, 1945-2011 AIS.2012.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Negatives, 1945-1998; II.
  - 120mm Negatives, 2.
    - 1991
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment; Murray Agency; Matthews International; Schuaubelt Shorts; St. Barnabas; PR Pictures; Ronig. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - St. Barnabas- Head Shots, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 39)
      - Murray Agency, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 40-41, 50-51)
      - Copies for St. Barnabas, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 42)
      - Matthews International, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 43)
      - Personal- 2.8 Rollei Test, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 44)
      - Ronig, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 45)
      - Copy for Al Saul, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 46)
      - Al Saul- Alcoa Plate, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 47)
      - Personna Grip (ED Dellis)- John Putzier PR Picture, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 48)
      - Personal- "SS", 1991 (Box 75, Folder 49)
      - For Al Saul "Paint Brush", 1991 (Box 75, Folder 52)
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 53-55)
      - Schnaubelt Shorts, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 56-57)
      - Personal- Fireworks- light up night, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 58-59)
      - Personal- Nature Images, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 60)
      - Lecture, 1991 (Box 75, Folder 61)
    - 1992
      Subjects include Schaubelt shorts. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Schnaubelt Shorts- Copy of magazine Cover, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 62)
      - Personal- 645 ETRS Test, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 63)
      - Personal- Pond Area, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 64)
      - Personal- Charlie T.J. Martin, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 65-66)
      - Schnaublet, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 67)
      - Personal- Trees & Pumpkin Patch at Farmers Market, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 68)
      - Personal- Nature Images, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 69)
      - Fireworks Over Pittsburgh, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 70-71)
      - Pittsburgh Night Shots, 1992 (Box 75, Folder 72-73)
    - 1993
      Subjects include Matthews International; Highlands; Schnaubelt. Also included are Martin's personal photographs and camera test photos.
      - Matthews International- 2 North Shore Center Offices, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 74)
      - Schnaubelt #1, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 75)
      - Schnaubelt #2, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 76)
      - Personal- Lens Test – Landscape, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 77-78)
      - Personal- McConnells Mill, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 79)
      - Personal- Hells Hollow, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 80)
      - Bashford's Tree, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 81-82)
      - Highlands – Laurel Gallery, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 83-84)
      - Personal- Lens Test, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 85)
      - Personal- Ocracoke, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 86-87)
      - Personal- Metzger on Cross Country Skiing, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 88)
      - PR Picture of Self, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 89)
      - Bronica 80mm Test, 1993 (Box 75, Folder 90)
    - 1994
      Subjects include McMill; St. Barnabas; McConnells Mill. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Personal- Rollei 3.5 Test- Tessar Test, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 1)
      - McConnells Mills, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 2, 8-15)
      - St. Barnabas- Dan Quayle Copy, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Personal- 3.5 Rollei, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Personal- Lens Test – after overhaul by Bald Mtn. Group, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 5)
      - Personal- Lens Test, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 6)
      - Personal- 252 Lincoln – Wall, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      - Condo Living Room, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 16)
      - Personal- 3.5F Xenotar Test, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 17-18)
      - Personal- Falls Off Rt 208, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 19-22)
      - Personal- Hike, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 23)
      - Personal- Ocracoke Trees, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 24)
      - Personal- Ocracoke Sunrise, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 25)
      - PR Shots, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 26)
      - St. Barnabas Copy- Group Shot w/ President Ford, Mr. & Mrs. Day, 1994 (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - 1995
      Subjects include St. Barnabas and Martin's personal photographs.
      - Personal- Novar Test, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 28)
      - Personal- Camera/Lens Test, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 29)
      - Personal, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 30)
      - Personal- Landscape, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 31-35)
      - Copy of Karen Myres'- Family Print, 1995 (Box 76, Folder 36)
    - 1996
      Subjects include Pittsburgh Sports Festival; St. Barnabas. Also included are Martin's Personal photographs.
      - Personal- Super Ikonta B, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 37)
      - Personal- St. Barnabas Copy, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 38)
      - Personal- Ikonta B (Novar), 1996 (Box 76, Folder 39)
      - Personal- Rollei 3.5F- McConnells Mill, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 40)
      - Violets & Dandelions, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 41-42)
      - Personal, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 43)
      - Copy- Loretta's Great Grandfather & Mother, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 44)
      - 3.5 Rollei, 1996 (Box 76, Folder 45)
    - 1997
      Subjects include Ocracoke Island, North Carolina; Daytona. Also included Martin's personal photographs.
      - Ron Muhlencamp, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 46)
      - Daytona Picture for Auto Trader, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 47)
      - Personal- Ikonta A, Novar Test, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 48)
      - Personal- PR Picture of Self, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 49)
      - Bridge – B'Falls & Ocracoke, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 50)
      - Personal- Cabin, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 51)
      - Personal- Landscape & Flowers, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 52)
      - Personal- Landscape, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 53)
      - Personal- Landscape/Forest, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 54-55, 57, 59-61)
      - Personal- Church Event, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 56)
      - Personal- Cottage, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 58)
      - Personal- Pitcairn Bridge, 1997 (Box 76, Folder 62)
    - 1998
      Subjects include Martin's personal photographs.
      - Personal- Novar Test- Sal & Bernice, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 62)
      - Ikonta B Novar- Knob Hill in Snow, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 64-65)
      - Personal- Cottage in Snow, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 66)
      - St. Barnabas - Copies, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 67)
      - Personal- Terry's Family Pictures Copies, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 68)
      - Lilypads, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 69)
      - Machinery Equipment, 1998 (Box 76, Folder 70)
  - 4 x 5 Negatives, 3.
    - 1966
      Subjects include Anderson Coupling Co.; Platts (Jack's Ford Dealership); Alcoa. McBeth; Bradford Wood Kindergarten. Also included are Martin's camera test photographs.
      - Miscellaneous Subjects ca. 1966-1967 (Box 77, Folder 1)
        This folder contains items from 1967 that had been filed together by the photographer who assigned the date range.
      - Kindergarten- Black and White, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 2)
      - Jack's Auto Dealership- Platts, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 3)
      - Alcoa- George McBeth, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 4)
      - Fire Truck- BWVFD, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 5)
      - Office Building- Anderson Coupling Company, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - 1967
      Subjects include McConnells Mills; Cross Electronics Inc.; Bradford Wood Kindergarten; McBeth- Geyser Job; Alcoa; Boy Scouts of America. Also included are Martins camera test photographs.
      - Boy Scouts of America- Camp Tionesta, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - 1968
      Subjects include the McBeth-Geyser Job; unidentified objects.
      - Geyser Job- George McBeth, 1968 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - 1973
      Subjects include Cross Electronics only.
      - Fuse Boxes- Cross Electric Company, 1973 (Box 77, Folder 8)
      - Voltage Teleductors- Cross Electric Company, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - 1974
      - Herr- Voss, 1974 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - 1975
      - Herr- Voss, 1975 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - 1976
      Subjects include McConnells Mills. Also included is Martin's camera test photographs.
      - Personal- Plus X Test- House, 1976 (Box 77, Folder 12)
      - McConnells Mills, 1976 (Box 77, Folder 13-)
    - 1978
      Subjects include Grinnell Co.(Fire Protection).
      - Grinnell Company, 1978 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - 1980
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1980 (Box 77, Folder 15-18)
    - 1981
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment; Red Cross; McConnells Mills. Also included are Martin's personal photographs.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 19-20, 22-24, 26)
      - Red Cross, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 21)
      - McConnells Mills, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 25)
      - Personal, 1981 (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - 1982
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment; scenic shots.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1982 (Box 77, Folder 28-32)
    - 1983
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment; unidentified objects.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 1-5)
      - Personal- Pittsburgh Skyline, 1983 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - 1984
      Subjects include Copper & Brass Sales.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 7-9, 11-12)
      - Copper and Brass Sales- Dan Stein, 1984 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - 1985
      Subjects include Gatan/ ACOCCA; Dynamic Energy; Sigma Chi Frat. Also included are Martin's camera test photographs.
      - Copper and Brass Sales, 1985 (Box 78, Folder 13)
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1985 (Box 78, Folder 14-16)
      - Personal, 1985 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - 1986
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment and Red Valve.
      - Red Valve, 1986 (Box 78, Folder 18)
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1986 (Box 78, Folder 19, 21, 23)
      - St. Barnabas (?), 1986 (Box 78, Folder 20)
      - Alphorn Itinerary, 1986 (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - 1987
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment; Red Valve; Alphorn Restaruant.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 23, 25-26)
      - Red Valve, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 24, 27)
    - 1988
      Subjects include ICI Co.; Dynamic Equipment.
      - ICI- Clay Pots, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 28)
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 29-30)
    - 1989
      - Personal- Trees & Pittsburgh Skyline- Copy Negatives, 1989 (Box 78, Folder 31)
    - 1990
      - International Images, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 1)
      - Columbus Museum, 1990 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - 1991
      Subjects include Matthew International.
      - Mathews, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 3)
      - Respighi & Art, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 4)
      - Newspaper Copy Photographs, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 5)
      - Personal- Landscape, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 6)
      - Personal- House, 1991 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - 1992
      - Hells Hollow, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 8)
      - Mathews, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 9)
      - McConnells Mills, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 10, 12)
      - Cucumber Falls, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 11)
      - Glacier, Montana, 1992 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - 1993
      Subjects include McConnolls Mill; Adirondaks; Glacier Mont.; Advertisements. Also included are Martin's camera test photographs.
      - McConnells Mills, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 14)
      - 210 Osaka Test, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 15)
      - Adirondacks, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 16)
      - (Pat) Nudi, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 17)
      - Personal- Buildings, 1993 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - 1996
      Subjects include Dynamic Equipment and Action Housing.
      - Dynamic Equipment Corporation, 1996 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - 1997
      Subjects include Pitcairn Bridge
      - Pitcairn Bridge, 1997 (Box 79, Folder 20)
      - Metropolitan Hall- 1800 Centre Avenue, 1997 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - 1998
      Subjects include 1800 Center Ave;Also included are Martin's camera test photographs.
      - TMY XTOL Test Xenar, 1998 (Box 79, Folder 22)
- Prints, 1950-2011; III.
  This series contains gelatin silver prints made from negatives taken by Martin. Topics include the Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, Pittsburgh, United Fund, Dyanamic Equipment, St. Barnabas, and French & Indian War, and Western PA History Sites & Reenactors, among others.
  - Western Pennsylvania School for Blind Children, 1970-1985 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Pittsburgh and Western Pennsylvania, 1950-2011 (Box 80, Folder 2-3)
    This folder contains images covering subjects such as a mining union boss; Market Square; Mellon Square; Somerset, PA., Memorial Day; Somersett County; Research in Hospitals; Pittsburgh Aquarium; Pittsburgh Blind Association; Pittsburgh city views; Pittsburgh Press Club; Allegheny County Soldiers & Sailors Memorial Hall and Museum; Hot Metal Bridge, Seven Springs Hotel; Great Allegheny Passage Bike Trail.
    Prominent people include President Gerald R. Ford; Mark Strickland; Senator H. John Heinz; Bill Burns (KDKA); Pittsburgh Mayor, Richard Caliguri; Kathryn Kuhlman.
  - United Way/United Fund, 1966-1985 (Box 80, Folder 4-5)
    This folder contains images covering subjects such as Big Brother; a United Way Board Meeting; the Speech and Hearing Society; Big Sisters; Vocational Rehab Center; Boys Club; Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh; Red Cross; Vintage Inc., Senior Center and Adult Day Center; Salvation Army; Visiting Nurses Association.
    Prominent people include Betty Roth, P.R. Director for United Way; Franco Harris; Tony Randall; and Bill Blass.
  - Western Pennsylvania French and Indian War History Sites and Reenactors, 2009 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    This folder contains images covering reenactments of the French & Indian War reenactors at Ft. Ligonier, Bushy Run, and Washington's Crossing- Connellsville.
  - Dynamic Equipment Corporation - North Side, 1980-1986 (Box 80, Folder 7-8)
    This folder contains cutouts of images Martin used for Dynamic Equipment.
  - St.Barnabas Inc., Gibsonia, 1981-1995 (Box 80, Folder 9-10)
    This folder contians images and information related to St. Barnabas Inc., and former President Gerald Ford visting St. Barnabas.
  - Regional Miscellaneous, 1950-1980 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    This folder contains images of North Park and North Park Lake; Big Brother; a Bessemer Converter; Manchester Craftsmen's Guild; Boy's Club; McConnells Mill; Dynamic Equipment; Ohio River.